Guide to British School Printing Examples
Yale University Arts Library
British School Printing Examples
1930-1984
AOB 14
Yale University Arts Library
2.5
(2 boxes)
Collection consists of various published works of printing schools and departments of British colleges, dating from 1930 to 1984.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
Collection consists of various published works of printing schools and departments of British colleges, dating from 1930 to 1984. The materials include monographic works on a variety of subjects, brochures, datebooks, keepsakes, etc., most of which were printed by students in fulfillment of academic requirements.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically by school. Where names of schools have changed over the years, the most recent name of each school represented in the collection is listed first, followed by previous names in parentheses.
Printing -- Study and teaching -- Great Britain
- Berkshire College of Art, Reading, 1963 (Box 1)
- Bolton College of Art, Department of Printing, 1960 (Box 1)
- Bristol School of Printing, College of Technology (Merchant Venturer's Technical College, School of Printing), 1934 1950-1952 undated (Box 1)
- Cambridgeshire College of Arts and Technology, 1969 (Box 1)
- Chester School of Art (College of Further Education, Chester, School of Art, Printing Section), 1971 1976 (Box 1)
- City of Birmingham School of Printing, College of Arts and Crafts, 1938 (Box 1)
- College of Technology, School of Art, Oxford (College of Technology Art and Commerce) (College of Technology, Department of Printing), 1957 1959 1961-1966 (Box 1)
- Duncan of Jordanstone College of Art, Department of Printing, 1963 (Box 1)
- Gloucester College of Art Printing Department (City of Gloucester College of Art, Department of Printing) (Gloucester and Cheltenham College of Art, Printing Department), 1956-1967 (Box 1)
- Kingston upon Hull at the Municipal College, School of Printing, 1930 (Box 1)
- Leicester College of Arts and Crafts (Box 1)
  General note
  See Box 2.
- London School of Printing (London College of Printing), 1947 1953 1965 1972 (Box 1)
- Maidstone College of Art, Department of Printing, 1952-1961 undated (Box 1)
- Napier College of Science and Technology, Department of Photography and Printing, Edinburgh, 1970 (Box 1)
- Northampton School of Art, Department of Printing, 1963 (Box 1)
- North-western Polytechnic, Department of Printing, London, 1954 (Box 1)
- Nottingham and District Technical College, Department of Printing, 1953 (Box 1)
- Reading Technical College, 1955 (Box 1)
- Tunbridge Wells School of Arts and Crafts, 1951 (Box 1)
- Leicester School of Printing, South Fields College (Leicester College of Arts and Crafts) (Leicester College of Art, School of Printing) (Leicester College of Art and Design, School of Printing), 1932-1984 (Box 2)